{
    "id": "e8e24e62b0854c65af80beeaa0b82219",
    "title": "Phrasal Verbs With Turn And Take",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "ce69f7aa67034da2a5c15da275e797e6",
            "title": "Phrasal Verbs With Turn Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The music is too loud. Please turn it .....................",
                    "description": "To turn down is to lower the volume. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "off",
                        "down",
                        "away"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "My application was turned ......................... because I didn't have the required qualifications.",
                    "description": "To turn down an application is to reject it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "away",
                        "off",
                        "down"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You are required to turn ....................... the report within a couple of days.",
                    "description": "To turn in a report is to submit it.",
                    "answers": [
                        "out",
                        "in",
                        "up"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am too tired to stay up. I think I should turn ..................... now",
                    "description": "To turn in is to go to bed. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "out",
                        "up",
                        "in"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He turns .................. a monster after he has had a couple of drinks.",
                    "description": "Turn into can mean transform. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "into",
                        "out",
                        "over"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Don't forget to turn ..................... the fan and the lights before you leave the room.",
                    "description": "To turn a device off is to stop it from working. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "up",
                        "away",
                        "off"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I had invited Samuel to my party but he didn't turn ..................",
                    "description": "To turn out is to attend an event. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "over",
                        "out",
                        "in"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I hadn't seen him for years. Then one day he turned .................. at my door.",
                    "description": "When someone turns up, they come unexpectedly. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "up",
                        "out",
                        "over"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you are not happy with the service you receive, you should take it .................... with the manager.",
                    "description": "To take something up with somebody is to complain to them about a problem. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "out",
                        "up",
                        "over"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I may take ..................... gardening after I retire.",
                    "description": "To take up something is to start doing it regularly. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "in",
                        "off",
                        "up"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I took my wife and children ...................... to dinner yesterday.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "in",
                        "out",
                        "over"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Germany will take .................... Argentina in the first semifinal on Friday.",
                    "description": "To take on somebody is to compete against them. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "over",
                        "on",
                        "up"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}